Welcome back.
In this lesson, we are going to see how to configure the timer to count the okay rules of the event,
the occurrence of an event could be the press of a button, the detection of the edge of a signal,
etc..
This is often known as the input capture mode of the timer.
And a mode such as this one is very important.
When you are dealing with some sensors, an example of that sense will be the ultrasonics central.
And for those of you who are not familiar with the, um, the mode of operation of the ultrasonic central,
well, what happens is that you have, um, you have an output piñon, an input pane, and basically
the output sends out a signal and then the signal would have to travel and then it would hit an object
and bounce back.
And then when it bounces back is going to be detected by the input spin and then the time it takes to
detect the signal.
The pretense is used to compute the distance of the object.
It's a very simple principle.
And if we're we're right in the, um, the drive off or on Ultrasonic Central, we'll be using inputs
capture all the time as a counter to capture when the signal returns.
So without talking much, let's just get into it.
In this in this example, though, we are going to simply detect the price of a war button on the board.
Well, I'm sure you'll be able to apply this principle in your everyday project.
I'll double click over here to get started.
I'll say no.
Over here.
A quote, a pinata by clicking pinata of a hit clip in out say yes if I hear.
And over here, we can make Hawaii experiment a bit more interesting, such that when we are able to
count the number of times the events will cast, we can blink on entity to do that.
I'm going to set out what Ellie Dippin here a you outputs like this.
Um, actually, I think we, um, we can see input's capture later this time, we're just going to use
time as a counter.
It's a different configuration compared to input's capture.
But this is there are some overlapping similarities.
Okay, so this time we are basically going to sort of capture the, um, the the the, um, the press
of the button.
So let's do it.
And you understand what I mean.
Come over here, timer.
And then also let time a one over here.
Then Luxor's or Select ETR, which is external external clock source.
iSelect, ETR.
Over here.
ETR to extend or Luxor's and everything else.
I'll leave it the same.
See?
OK, so Peter, twelve, ETR two.
OK.
For our club configuration here, we can leave everything the same.
Even if you have the Air Force, you board doesn't matter cause our club frequency is going to be based
on Dippin.
Because, um, our time out here, our time off, which is going to be the, um, what ETR here is a
different pin from where our push button SPC Fit and we're going to connect pieces fit in to Pier 12.
But if we had our button here, it would be fine.
But because we don't.
We're gonna.
Can I get.
If I hear I'm gonna set the, um, the counter period here to five.
I wouldn't set a pre-schooler counter period is basically just going to reload or to reload at five.
This is the value to which the auto reload happens.
So basically, when we detect, say, five, if you put ten here, we can auto reload at ten such that
when the event occurs for ten times, you can do an action.
In our case, when we detect five presses, we can, um, sort of toggle on LCD.
Next we go to the end, VIC searches and then we're going to take this one.
Hit the update.
Interrupt.
Over here.
Now we can go ahead and generate a project, I'll come to, um, January two right here, and then I'll
give the project any time a counter.
And then also light the torch and SDM 32.
Cuba makes, uh, Kubota e oh.
Click over here to generate.
We can open a project.
So over here, we simply need to implement a Kobuk, all the selections we made have been included in
our time.
And it's a function over here.
So to find a callback, we can just go to the, um, the time a module or come to drive this over here.
Hold driver and the source and then t i n c follow.
Give me that.
And um, I would just do control f and then I'll search under score week to jump to the callback.
The callback we're looking for is something like period elapsed callback.
It should be here somewhere.
OK.
It's over here.
He loves cool back.
Oh, copy this.
And I'll bring it to the main let's see over here.
I'll close this from here and then.
A patient above the main function over here and then cleanup within in here.
And we said one day when it lapses, we want to talk o the D.
I remember the period is going to elapse after with press of a button five times after its content.
Five course we set the auto reload to five.
So here we can simply say GPL you we can see how GPL you toggle pin.
So say how on a GPL you on a school.
Torgau pin and then pass the port GPL, you a then GPL, you on this call pin on the score five like
this.
Once we've implemented our Kobuk, we have to make sure we've started our time over to interrupt or
come down here and say HRO on this call.
Time on this call.
Start.
He has to be bass.
So I'll say I am bass.
Serve with the bass on the school, starts on the school I teach and then we pass the stress of the
time I handle h t.
I am one like this.
Okay, so we can build in c o click over here to build.
It's built successfully.
And then, um, we can go to the debugger or click on the bug over here.
So like we said earlier, our external trigger is set to be at 12:00 and we want to, you know, use
the button so we have to physically connect.
P a twelve and P.S. 13 using a jumper wire because we know our pattern is connected to 13.
Um, so we can, um, come over here.
Let's go back to our user guide and take a look at it.
Where was P twelve.
It's about.
Oh.
Open this up a bit.
Um.
So this is a twelve over here.
We have to put a jumper wire here.
One side of the jump, a wire and can make the other side two pieces, 13 over here.
Right.
Once we connect to the two things, we can simply run over here, we still in the pogo.
And as you can see, when I press when I press five times, it would Torgau, one, two, three, four,
five.
And then he came on.
One, two, three, four.
OK.
So what happens is sometimes you may realize that I press three times and then it goes.
This is.
This is because of a deep bounce.
When you press a button, you might think it's the you know, the signal has been read just once.
But sometimes you press a button and the press is recorded three times.
This can be eliminated using a filter, which is to write or write in a bit of code to get rid of typos.
But yet we're not looking at this now.
So I'll do it again.
One, two, three, four, five.
It's own.
One, two, three, four.
Cause I press too much.
Okay.
So they saw the rush and I'll see you in the next lesson.
Have a nice day.